

André Pinto

Nationality: Portuguese Date of birth: 07/12/2000 Gender: Male

📞 Phone number: (+351) 915641033 🔛 Email address: andrepintoimportante@proton.me

in LinkedIn: André Pinto

Website: https://github.com/AndrePintoProfile/

Website: https://andrepintoprofile.com/

O Home: Bairro do Vale Lote 7, 1 Drt, 3515-156 Viseu (Portugal)

ABOUT ME

I am a programmer with over five years of experience at Deloitte, specializing in **automated testing** using **Robot Framework** and **Selenium**. I am currently completing a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering on a part-time basis, which highlights my ability to manage time effectively and my commitment to the continuous improvement of my technical and professional skills. I have experience with various technologies, including **OutSystems** and **JavaScript**, as well as strong skills in **communication**, **teamwork**, and **problem-solving**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer

Deloitte [09/2024 - Current]

City: Viseu | Country: Portugal

- Focus in development and implementation of automated tests using Robot Framework and Selenium.
- Collaboration with multidisciplinary teams, ensuring clear communication between stakeholders and the technical team.
- Support in troubleshooting technical issues and improving processes.

Developer and BrightStart Program Student

Deloitte [09/2019 - 08/2024]

City: Viseu | Country: Portugal

- Development and implementation of **automated tests** using **Robot Framework** and **Selenium**.
- Creation and maintenance of solutions in **OutSystems**, including **API** integrations and the development of responsive applications.
- Collaboration with multidisciplinary teams, ensuring clear communication between stakeholders and the technical team.
- Support in troubleshooting technical issues and improving processes.

Internship in Computer Maintenance

Câmara Municipal de Resende [02/2019 – 04/2019]

City: Resende | Country: Portugal

- Computer maintenance and technical support.
- Customer service and resolution of technical issues.

Internship in Web Application Development

PI Soluções [06/2018 - 07/2018]

City: Viseu | Country: Portugal

- Development and maintenance of websites using WordPress.
- Interaction with clients to gather requirements and implement customized solutions.

Internship in Computer Maintenance

Câmara Municipal de Resende [07/2017 – 07/2017]

City: Resende | Country: Portugal

- Computer maintenance and technical support.
- Customer service and resolution of technical issues.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

Instituto Politécnico de Viseu [09/2021 – Current]

City: Viseu | Country: Portugal | Website: https://ipv.pt/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Higher Professional Technical Course in Web and Mobile Device Development

Instituto Politécnico de Viseu [09/2019 – 07/2021]

City: Viseu | Country: Portugal | Website: https://ipv.pt/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Professional Course in Computer Systems Management and Programming Technician

Escola Secundária Dom Egas Moniz [09/2016 - 07/2019]

City: Resende | Country: Portugal | Website: https://aeresende.pt/escolas/es-resende/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 4

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Digital Skills - Test Results

	Information and data literacy	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
<u>®</u> ₩	Communication and collaboration	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
©	Digital content creation	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
Zh)	Safety	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
	Problem solving	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6

Results from <u>self-assessment</u> based on <u>The Digital Competence Framework 2.1</u>

My Digital Skills

Technical Skills

Automated Testing Development / Robot Framework / Selenium / Outsystems / X-Ray / Jira / Github / Git / JavaScript / Node.js / Express.js / APIs / Java / SQL / HTML / CSS / Wordpress

Soft Skills

Teamwork / Effective communication / Client relationship / Business requirements / Problem solving / Time management and multitasking / Productivity and Initiative

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B1

Driving Licence: B

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Technology

I love buying new gadgets, building PCs, hardware, etc.

Gaming

I love playing computer games, especially those related to science fiction and space.